<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Swastik Banerjee</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Swastik Banerjee</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 08:10:55 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/posts/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Sep 2025 08:10:55 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/about/</guid>
      <description>&amp;#34;Life is Complex. It has Real and Imaginary parts.&#34; Hi, I’m Swastik, but you’ll often find me as <strong>justanotherlad</strong> on the Internet. I am a Software Engineer at <strong>Microsoft AI</strong> (Bing/Copilot Search) based in Hyderabad, India.<br> Before this, I was working remotely as the Lead Search Engineer for <strong>Wolfram Alpha</strong>.<br><br> In my last 4 years in the industry, I have worked on developing and maintaining high-QPS and low-latency (backend) systems handling Search Relevance, Ranking, e2e RAG systems (hybrid search, i.e., lexical + semantic search using dense retrieval/vector-embeddings + sparse/BM25 mechanisms) and maximizing user experience & engagement by handling the UX/Frontend of <a href="https://www.bing.com/search?q=fever+symptoms#:~:text=People%20also%20ask">bing.com</a> (<strong>People Also Ask</strong> answer) and <a href="https://search.wolfram.com/">search.wolfram.com</a> websites.<br><br> I started-off in the industry as a Summer Researcher followed by a 9-month long Intern at Wolfram, where I worked on several R&D projects related to symbolic computation & computer algebraic systems. Prior to that, I did a summer internship at the end of my 2nd year of college at the <strong>Indian Statistical Institute, Kolkata</strong> at their R.C. Bose Centre for Cryptology and Security funded by <em>Microsoft Research India</em>, where I developed APIs to automate linear and differential cryptanalysis-check for block ciphers.<br> Somewhere in the middle I was also associated with <strong>IBM Research India</strong> as a Part-time Research Assistant under Staff Research Scientist of IBM Quantum + AI Innovation dept., <a href="https://research.ibm.com/people/dhinakaran-vinayagamurthy">Dhinakaran Vinayagamurthy</a>, where I worked on some Applied Cryptography projects, particularly on Differential Privacy and Multi-Party Computation.<br><br> I have completed my undergraduation in Computer Science, with major in Information Technology.
<br>My primary interests are Information Retrieval, Conversational systems, Applied Cryptography, Discrete Mathematics and Music-making.
<br>I&rsquo;m also trying to explore other areas of computer science and cyber-security.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
